>> 이번에는 LSTM에 대해서 배우보겠습니다.
>> This is where LSTMs come in.
LSTM은 long short-term memory의 약자입니다.
LSTM stands for long short-term memory.
개념적으로 recurrent neural network은
단순하고 작은 반복적인 구조를 이루어졌으며,
Now, conceptually, a recurrent neural
network consists of a repetition of
과거의 입력된 값과 새로운 입력값들을 가지고 있으며,
simple little units like this,
which take as an input the past,
새로운 예측값을 생성하고 그것을 다음에 연결합니다.
a new inputs, and produces a new
prediction and connects to the future.
중앙에 있는 값은 전형적인 layer 구조를 갖습니다.
Now, what's in the middle of that is
typically a simple set of layers.
어떤 가중치와 어떤 선형성은 갖는 전형적인 neural network임.
Some weights and some linearities.A
typical neural network.
LSTMs을 가지고
With LSTMs,
우리는 이상한 작은 머신을 갖는
조금한 모듈로 교체할 것입니다.
we're going to replace this little
module with a strange little machine.
이것은 복잡하게 보여지지만,
기능적으로 neural net입니다.
It will look complicated, but
it's still functionally a neural net.
그리고 RNN에서 그것을 drop할 수 있고
그것에 대한 걱정할 것이 없습니다.
And you can drop it into your RNN and
not worry about it.
이 아키텍처에 대해서 모든 것은 동일하고,
Everything else about the architecture
remains the same, and
이것은 훌륭하게 vanishing gradient 문제를
줄여줍니다.
it greatly reduces
the vanishing gradient problem.